Now we're going to talk about recovering a dropped stitch.
You can even use a pencil or a crochet hook or a sewing needle.
You just go in, you pull it back up and you're good to go.
Let's finish this row.
Knit.
Now I'm happy.
I'm back to my regular number of stitches and everything is easy.
Now, I know I only dropped one stitch that time, but let's pretend that I had dropped another just for practice.
I have this here.
What I would do is I would go in here, wiggle that stitch on up, up and back, and put it up on there.
Now all you do is knit that stitch and you've saved your dropped stitch.
Isn't that exciting?
Let's say that you want to rip something out.
To rip something out, you would take the needle and you go right underneath.
This is a good example because we have a different color.
You would pull that there, go back in there, and pull there and you're out a stitch.
Does that make sense?
Let me do it again.
Let's say that you want to unravel a stitch at a time.
Instead of going and pulling on it and yank, yank, yank, yank, what you do is you go and you let it off the hook and you pull that stitch down there.
See that?
I'm letting that black and white baby go because I want to get rid of it.
This one I'm just going to knit because we're at the end of the row.
We're now at black and white.